As a first example,
第一个示例
let's apply this new idea of notation to something you've used before.
我们将这种符号表达式的思维 运用到用过的工具上
Spreadsheets. Spreadsheets are a common way we hold data in the real world.
该工具是电子表格 它是我们在实际生活中 存储数据的常用方式
In our spreadsheet, we have rows and columns.
在电子表格中有行和列
To better understand how we use spreadsheets to hold data,
为了更好地理解如何使用电子表格存储数据
let's work through an example.
我们看一个示例
Before even collecting data,
在收集数据之前
we usually start with a question or many questions.
我们通常以一个问题或多个问题开始
Consider I run a small blog about my
假设我开设了一个博客
best and worst adventures with the dogs at the coffee shop.
内容是关于和咖啡厅中狗狗的最佳经历以及最糟糕经历
Which also sells trinkets related to those adventures.
并且还会出售一些与这些经历相关的小商品
Everything from fetch toys to leashes,
抓取玩具、狗链
to doggie bags, and everything in between.
以及狗袋 等等
Questions I might have are: How many people visit my site?
我可能会问的问题是 有多少人访问了我的网站？
Or how much time do visitors spend on my site?
或者访问者在我的网站上停留了多长时间？
Are there differences in traffic,
根据周几的不同
depending on the day of the week?
网站流量有区别吗？
How many visitors purchase an item through the blog?
有多少访问者通过该博客购买了小商品？
In order to answer these questions,
为了回答这些问题
say we keep track of the date of the visit,
假设我们记录了访问日期
the day of the week of the visit,
在一周的那一天访问
the amount of time spent on the site,
在网站上停留的时间
and whether or not an individual buys an item.
以及用户是否购买了商品
We can think of each of these as a column.
可以将所有这些问题每个看做一列
A column in our dataset is associated with a random variable.
数据集中的一列指的是随机变量
Explaining what a random variable is in English is complicated.
用文字解释随机变量是什么很复杂
But in notation, it's simple.
但是用符号的话 就很简单
In English, a random variable is a placeholder for the possible values of some process.
用文字解释 随机变量是指某些流程的可能取值的占位符
In notation, it's X.
用符号表示的话 就是 X
For our website, the date of the visit,
对于我们的网站 访问日期
the day of the week of the visit,
一周的某一天
the amount of time spent on the site,
在网站上花费的时间
and whether or not an individual buys an item are all variables.
用户是否购买了商品都是变量
Let's say we have a visitor on Thursday, June 15.
假设在 6 月 15 日 周四 有位访问者
The visitor stays on our site for five minutes and doesn't buy an item.
该访问者在网站上停留了 5 分钟 没有购买商品
Then a second visitor,
第二位访问者
visits the site on the exact same day for 10 minutes and they do buy an item.
在同一天停留了 10 分钟 购买了商品
Notice how each of these individuals has been added to our spreadsheet.
注意每位用户是如何添加到电子表格的
We might have many more visitors,
我们可能有更多的访问者
and we could update our spreadsheet accordingly.
可以相应地更新电子表格
When using spreadsheets, we frequently
在使用电子表格时
analyze a full column to answer our questions of interest.
我们经常会分析整个列来回答问题
For example, to answer the question of how much time do visitors spend on our site?
例如 要回答访问者在我们的网站上花费了多长时间
We need to look at this column.
我们需要查看这一列
To answer the question of,
为了回答
Are there differences in traffic,
在一周的每一天
depending on the day of the week?
流量之间的差别
We need to look at this column.
我们需要查看这一列
And to answer the question of,
为了回答
How many purchases occur through our blog?
通过该博客售出了多少商品
We need to look at this column.
我们需要查看这一列
Mathematically, we usually consider a random variable or column using a capital letter.
从数学角度来看 我们通常用大写字母表示随机变量或列
Commonly, we use the capital letter X,
经常使用大写字母 X
but we can just as easily use Y,
但是也可以使用 Y、Z
Z or any other capital letter.
或任何其他大写字母
We might say, consider the random variable X,
我们可以假设 随机变量 X
which signifies the amount of time an individual spends on our website.
它表示单个用户在我们的网站上花费的时间
Therefore, X relates to this entire column.
因此 X 与这一整列有关
Consider we also have a random variable Y,
假设还有一个随机变量 Y
which signifies whether or not an individual purchases an item from the website,
表示单个用户是否从我们的网站购买了商品
so Y relates to this entire column.
因此 Y 与这一整列有关